// Creating an Array and passing the number, questions, options and answers

let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1,
        question: "The correct sequence of reproductive stages seen in flowering plants is",
        answer: "gametes, zygote, embryo, seedling",
        options: [
            "zygote, gametes, embryo, seedling",
            "gametes, zygote, embryo, seedling",
            "seedling, embryo, zygote, gametes",
            "gametes, embryo, zygote, seedling"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2,
        question: "Keeping the potential difference constant, the resistance of the circuit is halved. The current will become:",
        answer: "double",
        options: [
            "One-fourth",
            "four times",
            "half",
            "double"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: "It is necessary to balance a chemical equation in order to satisfy the law of:",
        answer: "Conservation of mass",
        options: [
            "Conservation of motion",
            "Conservation of momentum",
            "Conservation of energy",
            "Conservation of mass"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        question: "In human males, the testes lie in the scrotum, because it helps in the",
        answer: "formation of sperm",
        options: [
            "process of mating",
            "formation of sperm",
            "easy transfer of gametes",
            "all of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        question: "Two electric bulbs have resistances in the ratio 1:2. If they are joined in series, the energy consumed in them is in the ratio.",
        answer: "1:2",
        options: [
            "2:1",
            "1:2",
            "4:1",
            "1:4"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        question: "Which of the following gases is used in the storage of fat and oil containing foods for a long time?",
        answer: "Nitrogen gas",
        options: [
            "Carbondioxide gas",
            "Nitrogen gas",
            "Oxygen gas",
            "Neon gas"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7,
        question: "Reproduction is essential for living organisms in order to",
        answer: "continue the species generation after generation",
        options: [
            "keep the individual organism alive",
            "fulfill their energy requirement",
            "maintain growth",
            "continue the species generation after generation"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        question: "If length of a conductor and it's radius is increased twice, how the resistance will change?",
        answer: "Resistance will become half",
        options: [
            "Resistance will remain unchanged",
            "Resistance increase twice",
            "Resistance will become half",
            "Resistance will increase 4 times"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        question: "Name the gas that is evolved by the reaction of Zinc and Dilute Sulphuric Acid?",
        answer: "Hydrogen",
        options: [
            "Hydrogen",
            "Carbondioxide",
            "Magnesium Oxide",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        question: "The process of transfer of pollen grains from the anther to the stigma of same flower or another flower of the same plantis called?",
        answer: "None of these",
        options: [
            "Fission",
            "Fertilization",
            "Fragmentation",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11,
        question: "The filament of bulb is made of which of the following materials?",
        answer: "Tungsten",
        options: [
            "Gold",
            "Silver",
            "Platinum",
            "Tungsten"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12,
        question: "The chemical reaction between sulphuric acid and barium chloride solution is characterised by the formation of?",
        answer: "Barium sulphate",
        options: [
            "barium chlorite",
            "hydrochloric acid",
            "sulphuric acid",
            "Barium sulphate"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13,
        question: "A feature of reproduction that is common to Amoeba, Yeast and Spirogyra is that",
        answer: "they reproduce asexually",
        options: [
            "they reproduce asexually",
            "they are all unicellular",
            "they are all multicellular",
            "they reproduce only sexually"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 14,
        question: "Two devices are connected between two points say A and B in parallel. The physical quantity that will remain the same between the two points is",
        answer: "Voltage",
        options: [
            "Current",
            "Voltage",
            "resistance",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 15,
        question: "Oxidation is a process which involves",
        answer: "addition of oxygen",
        options: [
            "addition of oxygen",
            "addition of hydrogen",
            "removal of oxygen",
            "removal of hydrogen"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 16,
        question: "The process of the division of cell into several cells during reproduction in Plasmodium is termed as:",
        answer: "Multiple Fission",
        options: [
            "Fragmentation",
            "Budding",
            "Multiple Fission",
            "Binary Fission"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 17,
        question: "Electrical resistivity of a given metallic wire depends upon",
        answer: "Nature of the Material",
        options: [
            "Length",
            "Thickness",
            "Nature of the Material",
            "Shape"
        ]
    },
];